<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
       <name>Death Sorcerous Origin</name>
       <description>5e homebrew</description>
       <author url="https://github.com/NOS1996">NOS</author>
       <update version="0.0.4">
           <file name="Death Sorcery.xml" url="https://github.com/NOS1996/Component-DnD/blob/master/Death-Sorcery.xml" />
       </update>
    </info>
	<element name="Death Sorcery" type="Archetype" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_SORCERY">
		<supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have been touched by death. And its mark on you grants you the ability to bend the world to your will.</p>
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_EXTENDED_MAGIC" />
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_SOUL_HARVEST" />
     		<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_IMPROVED_SOUL_HARVEST" />
     		<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_DEATHS_WARD" />
     		<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_LORD_OF_DEATH" />
     		<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_ANIMATE" />
     		<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_AURA_OF_DEATH" />
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have been touched by death.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_EXTENDED_MAGIC" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_SOUL_HARVEST" level="3" />
     		<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_IMPROVED_SOUL_HARVEST" level="6"/>
 			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_DEATHS_WARD" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_LORD_OF_DEATH" level="18" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_ANIMATE" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_AURA_OF_DEATH" level="16" />
		</rules>
	</element>
 <element name="Aura of Death" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS"  id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_AURA_OF_DEATH">
    <description>
      <p>Beginning at 16th level an aura surrounds you and saps the life of anything within 10 feet of you. If a creature ends its turn within range it must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or lose hit points equal to the number of souls you have stored. You gain hit points equal to half the hit points the creature lost, rounded up.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>An aura surrounds you and saps the life of anything within 10 feet of you. If a creature ends its turn within range it must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or lose hit points equal to the number of souls you have stored. You gain hit points equal to half the hit points the creature lost, rounded up.</description>
    </sheet>
 </element>	
 <element name="Animate" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_ANIMATE">
    <description>
      <p>At level 14th level, the repetitive nature of raising your undead has become like a ritual for you. You may cast <i>animate dead</i> as a ritual.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You may cast <i>animate dead</i> as a ritual.</description>
    </sheet>
 </element>
	    <element name="Deaths Ward" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_DEATHS_WARD">
        <description>
            <p>You are immune to radiant and necrotic damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You are immune to radiant and necrotic damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_RADIANT" />
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_NECROTIC" />
        </rules>
    </element>
	<element name="Extended Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_EXTENDED_MAGIC">
		<description>
			<p>Your heritage grants you powers considered unnatural.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description level="3">You gain 3 additional sorcery points.</description>
			<description level="6">You gain 6 additional sorcery points.</description>
			<description level="12">You gain 9 additional sorcery points.</description>
			<description level="18">You gain 12 additional sorcery points.</description>
		</sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="sorcery-points" value="3" level="3" />
            <stat name="sorcery-points" value="3" level="6" />
            <stat name="sorcery-points" value="3" level="12" />
            <stat name="sorcery-points" value="3" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Soul Harvest" type="Class Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_SOUL_HARVEST">
    	<description>
     	 <p> At the end of your turn, if you or any undead under your control have killed one or more creatures, you gain hit points equal to your sorcerer level. If doing so would grant you more hit points than you can have, you gain temporary hit points equal to the amount of excess hit points received.</p>
   		</description>
    	 <sheet>
     	   <description>At the end of your turn, if you or any undead under your control have killed one or more creatures, you gain {{level:sorcerer}} hit points. If doing so would grant you more hit points than you can have, you gain temporary hit points equal to the amount of excess hit points received.</description>
    	  </sheet>
  	</element>
 	<element name="Improved Soul Harvest" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_IMPROVED_SOUL_HARVEST">
    	<description>
      <p>Starting at 6th level, you've gained the knowledge to channel the souls you harvest into your spells. You may store a number of souls equal to twice your sorcerer level from killing creatures with soul harvest for later use. You can consume souls to regain either sorcery points or up to a 6th level spell slot, which costs 2 souls for a 1st level spell and every additional spell level beyond. For instance, a 3rd level spell would consume 6 souls and one sorcery point would consume 2 souls. In addition, when you deal damage to a creature with a spell, you may consume any number of souls in your possession to deal additional necrotic damage equal to the number of souls you consume. </p>
    	</description>
    	<sheet>
      	<description>You may store {{level*2} souls from killing creatures with soul harvest. You can consume souls to regain either sorcery points or up to a 6th level spell slot, which costs 2 souls per spell level slot/sorcery point. When you deal damage to a creature, you may consume any number of souls in your possession to deal additional necrotic damage equal to the number of souls you consume.</description>
    	</sheet>
  	</element>
  	<element name="Lord of Death" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEATH_SORCERY_LORD_OF_DEATH">
		<description>
			<p>At 18th level, you gain the ability to step from one shadow into another. When you are in dim light or darkness, as a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 120 feet to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in dim light or darkness. When you are hit by an attack, you can use your reaction to deal necrotic damage to the attacker. The damage equals your sorcerer level, and ignores resistance to necrotic damage.In addition, any spell or effect you create ignores resistance to necrotic damage and treats immunity to necrotic damage as resistance to necrotic damage. Your newfound affinity towards darkness also grants you darkvision out to 120 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you are in dim light or darkness you can (as a bonus action) magically teleport up to 120 feet to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in dim light or darkness.When you are hit by an attack, you can use your reaction to deal {{level:sorcerer}} necrotic damage to the attacker. In addition, any spell or effect you create ignores resistance to necrotic damage and treats immunity to necrotic damage as resistance to necrotic damage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
