<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Shield Warden</name>
    <update version="0.0.1">
      <file name="Shield-Warden.xml" url="https://github.com/NOS1996/Component-DnD/blob/master/Shiled-Warden.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>

  	<element name="Shield Warden" type="Archetype" source="Surrealistik" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_SHIELD_WARDEN">
		<supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Some martial proffessionals, most commonly thoose charged with work as bodyguards and guardians, are practitioners of a rarefied magical power, that enables them to project a protective arcane barrier. This shielding force is unusual in such a way that it draws from the users vital force and is not invoked by mere incantations. Skilled weilders of this protective forceare able to turn away even the deadliest and most withering attacks with casual ease.</p>
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_AEGIS" />
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_REPELLING_FORCE" />
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_SWIFT_BARRIER" />
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_REGENERATIVE_WARD" />
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_INVIOLABLE_PROTECTION" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_AEGIS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_REPELLING_FORCE" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_SWIFT_BARRIER" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_REGENERATIVE_WARD" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_INVIOLABLE_PROTECTION" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Aegis" type="Archetype Feature" source="Surrealistik" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_AEGIS">
		<description>
			<p>Upon choosing this archetype at 3rd level, you are able to create a faintly glowing shield of arcane force.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can activate or deactivate a magical barrier. This barrier has hit points equal to twice your Constitution modifier plus twice your Fighter level and regains all hit points whenever you finish a long rest. While this barrier is active, you radiate dim light in a 5 foot radius. This barrier deactivates automatically whenever you become unconscious, or when it is reduced to 0 hit points.</p>
			<p class="indent">While your barrier is active, whenever a creature or object you can see would take damage while within 10 feet of you, you can use your reaction to hae the barrier take that damage instead. If this damage reduces the barrier to 0 hit points, that creature or object takes any remaining damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Further, whenever you would regain hit points, you can have your barrier regain those hit points instead, plus extra hit points of half your Fighter level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
			<p action="bonus action">You can activate or deactivate a magical barrier. This barrier has {{barrier-hp}} hit points and regains all hit points whenever you finish a long rest. While this barrier is active, you radiate dim light in a 5 foot radius. This barrier deactivates automatically whenever you become unconscious, or when it is reduced to 0 hit points.</p>
			<p action="reaction">While your barrier is active, whenever a creature or object you can see would take damage while within 10 feet of you, you can use the barrier to take that damage instead. If this damage reduces the barrier to 0 hit points, that creature or object takes any remaining damage.</p>
			<p>Further, whenever you regain hit points, you can have your barrier regain those hit points instead, plus {{extra-hp}} .
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="barrier-hp" value="level:fighter" />
			<stat name="barrier-hp" value="level:fighter" />
			<stat name="barrier-hp" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="barrier-hp" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="extra-hp" value="level:fighter:half:up" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Repelling Force" type="Archetype Feature" source="Surrealistik" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_REPELLING_FORCE">
		<description>
			<p>At 7th level you can shape your barrier's energies into a driving blast of nigh irresistible force.</p>
			<p class="indent"> As a bonus action, you can expend an amount of your Aegis hit points equal to one and a half times your fighter level to deal an equal amount of force damage to a creature you can see within the barriers range. If you do so the target must succed on a Strength saving throw with a DC of 8 + your strength modifier + your consitution modifier. On a failure for each 5 points of damage dealt to the target, you can push it up  to 5 feet away from you.</p>
			<p class="indent">Furthermore, until the end of your next turn, while your barrier is active, spaces within its range count as difficult terrain to the target.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
			<p action="bonus action">You can expend an amount of your Aegis hit points equal to {{force-hp}} to deal an equal amount of force damage to a creature you can see within the barriers range. If you do so the target must succed on a Strength saving throw with a DC of {{force-dc}} . On a failure for each 5 points of damage dealt to the target, you can push it up to 5 feet away from you.</p>
			<p>Until the end of your next turn, while your barrier is active, spaces within its range count as difficult terrain to the target of your repelling force.</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="force-hpce" value="level:fighter" />
			<stat name="force-hp" value="level:fighter:half" />
			<stat name="force-dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="force-dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="force-dc" value="strength:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Swift Barrier" type="Archetype Feature" source="Surrealistik" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_SWIFT_BARRIER">
		<description>
			<p>At 10th level, utilizing your barrier has become all but second nature, allowing you to direct its energies with casual ease.</p>
			<P class="indent">Twice per turn you can redirect damage to your Aegis without using your reaction.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="2/turn">
			<description>Redirect damage to your Aegis without using your reaction.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Regenerative Ward" type="Archetype Feature" source="Surrealistik" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_REGENERATIVE_WARD">
		<description>
			<p>At 15th level, growing mastery ovre your shield allows you to gradually albeit partially reform it.</p>
			<p class="indent">At the start of each of your turns, while you are concious your Aegis regains hit points equal to your constitution modifier if it has at least 1 hit point and less than half its hit point maximum.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While you are concious your Aegis regains {{regain-hp}} hit points if it has at least 1 hit point and less than half its hit point maximum.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="regain-hp" value="constitution:modifier"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Inviolable Protection" type="Archetype Feature" source="Surrealistik" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIELD_WARDEN_INVIOLABLE_PROTECTION">
		<description>
			<p>At 18th level your barrier becomes a nigh impenetrable force to all but most legendary and most determined foes. You gain the following benfits</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><em>None without Shelter</em></b>The range of your Aegis increases to 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><em>Bladebane Aegis</em></b>Your Aegis has resistance to damage from nonmagical attacks.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><em>Prismatic Ward</em></b>Whenever you complete a short or long rest, choose two damage types (other than slashing, bludgeoning and piercing. Your Aegis has resistance to these damage types until the end of your next short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<descriptio>
			 <p>You gain the following benefits:</p>
			 <p class="indent"><b><em>None without Shelter</em></b>The range of your Aegis increases to 30 feet.</p>
			 <p class="indent"><b><em>Bladebane Aegis</em></b>Your Aegis has resistance to damage from nonmagical attacks.</p>
			 <p class="indent"><b><em>Prismatic Ward</em></b>Whenever you complete a short or long rest, choose two damage types (other than slashing, bludgeoning and piercing. Your Aegis has resistance to these damage types until the end of your next short or long rest.</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>