<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Starlight</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="starlight.xml" url="https://github.com/NOS1996/Component-DnD/blob/master/Starlight.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Starlight" type="Archetype" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_STARLIGHT">
		<supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Magic is the center of your world like the sun is the center of the solar system. You draw power from the light of the stars, and so over time became one yourself</p>
			<p class="indent">Starlighters condemn all forces of darkness and strive, much like Paladins to rid the worlds of their evil. They strive to hunt down and eliminate magical threats and extraplanar entities, leaving only clairvoyant beauty in their wake.</p>
			<p class="indent">Starlighters can most be found in Ben'nir, Elven or Fey communities, although in some human settlements you might find one or two Starlighters to secure their landly life.</p>
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_OZON_LAYER" />
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_CELESTIAL_FIRE" />
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_SOLAR_ORBIT" />
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_SOLAR_ORDER" />
			<div element="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_BLACK_HOLE" />
		 </description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Starlighters strive to rid the worlds of their evil.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_OZON_LAYER" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_CELESTIAL_FIRE" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_SOLAR_ORBIT" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_SOLAR_ORDER" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_BLACK_HOLE" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>


	<element name="Celestial Fire" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_CELESTIAL_FIRE">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 2nd level your spells and cantrips deal an additional 1d8 radiant damage. Furthermore your spells that deal radiant damage treat immunity to radiant damage as resistance to radiant damage, and ignore resistance to radiant damage. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your spells and cantrips that deal damage deal an additional 1d8 radiant damage. Furthermore your spells that deal radiant damage treat immunity to radiant damage as resistance to radiant damage, and ignore resistance to radiant damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Ozon Layer" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_OZON_LAYER">
		<description>
			<p>When you adopt this tradition at 2nd level, you gain proficiency with light armor, and you have advantage on saving throws against spells.</p>
			<p class="indent">You also gain proficiency in the Perception skill if you don’t already have it.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on saving throws against spells.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_GFP_COFSA_SPELL_ANGELIC_REBUKE" spellcasting="Wizard"/>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_GFP_COFSA_SPELL_FLASHING_BLADES" spellcasting="Wizard" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_GFP_COFSA_SPELL_HALO" spellcasting="Wizard" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_GFP_COFSA_SPELL_PUNISHING_SMITE" spellcasting="Wizard" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CROWN_OF_STARS" spellcasting="Wizard" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DAWN" spellcasting="Wizard" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FIND_GREATER_STEED" spellcasting="Wizard" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_HOLY_WEAPON" spellcasting="Wizard" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WORD_OF_RADIANCE" spellcasting="Wizard" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT" spellcasting="Wizard" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_CELESTIAL" spellcasting="Wizard" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Solar Orbit" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_SOLAR_ORBIT">
		<description>
			<p>At 6th level, you can forge a magical bond with a weapon. Choose a weapon in which you are proficient. Performing the bonding ritual takes 1 hour, which may be done during a short rest. The weapon must be within your reach throughout the ritual.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can’t be disarmed of your bonded weapon as long as you are concious, also it may not be used by any creature other than you. If it is on the same plane of existence, you can summon that weapon as a bonus action on your turn, causing it to teleport instantly to your hand. If you attempt to bond to another weapon, you must break the bond with the first.</p>
			<p class="indent">While your bond exists, you can use your spellcasting ability for the attack and damage rolls of attacks using that weapon. The weapon also becomes magical, if it isn’t already. At 10th level, your effectiveness with the weapon improves as it gains a bonus of +1 to attack and damage rolls, and then again to a +2 bonus at 14th level.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Choose a weapon in which you are proficient. Performing the bonding ritual takes 1 hour, which may be done during a short rest. The weapon must be within your reach throughout the ritual.
			You can’t be disarmed of your bonded weapon as long as you are concious, also it may not be used by any  creature other than you. If it is on the same plane of existence, you can summon that weapon as a bonus action on your turn, causing it to teleport instantly to your hand. If you attempt to bond to another weapon, you must break the bond with the first.
			While your bond exists, you can use your spellcasting ability for the attack and damage rolls of attacks using that weapon. The weapon also becomes magical, if it isn’t already.</description>
			<description level="10">Choose a weapon in which you are proficient. Performing the bonding ritual takes 1 hour, which may be done during a short rest. The weapon must be within your reach throughout the ritual.
			You can’t be disarmed of your bonded weapon as long as you are concious, also it may not be used by any  creature other than you. If it is on the same plane of existence, you can summon that weapon as a bonus action on your turn, causing it to teleport instantly to your hand. If you attempt to bond to another weapon, you must break the bond with the first.
			While your bond exists, you can use your spellcasting ability for the attack and damage rolls of attacks using that weapon. The weapon also becomes magical, if it isn’t already. Your effectiveness with the weapon improves as it gains a bonus of +1 to attack and damage rolls.</description>
			<description level="14">Choose a weapon in which you are proficient. Performing the bonding ritual takes 1 hour, which may be done during a short rest. The weapon must be within your reach throughout the ritual.
			You can’t be disarmed of your bonded weapon as long as you are concious, also it may not be used by any  creature other than you. If it is on the same plane of existence, you can summon that weapon as a bonus action on your turn, causing it to teleport instantly to your hand. If you attempt to bond to another weapon, you must break the bond with the first.
			While your bond exists, you can use your spellcasting ability for the attack and damage rolls of attacks using that weapon. The weapon also becomes magical, if it isn’t already. Your effectiveness with the weapon improves as it gains a bonus of +2 to attack and damage rolls.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Solar Order" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_SOLAR_ORDER">
  		<description>
   		 <p>Beginning at 10th level, while you are concentrating on a spell, your concentration can’t be broken. Furthermore, you have resistance to the damage of spells. All spells you cast that deal fire damage, count as radiant in regards to your Celestial Fire feature.</p>
  		</description>
  		<sheet>
   		 <description>While you are concentrating on a spell, your concentration can’t be broken. Furthermore, you have resistance to the damage of spells. All spells you cast that deal fire damage, count as radiant in regards to your Celestial Fire feature.</description>
  		</sheet>
	</element>
 	<element name="Black Hole" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARLIGHT_BLACK_HOLE">
   	 <description>
     	 <p>Starting at 14th level, you absorb parts of the magic that surrounds you. Whenenver you cast a spell, are subject of a spell, trigger a spell or enter the area effect of a spell, you gain hit points equal to twice the level of the spell. If doing so would grant you more hit points than you can have, you gain temporary hit points, that do not vanish after long rests, equal to the amount of excess hit points received. Furthermore you gain a number of weave points equal to the level of the spell. You may store up to {{weave-points}} weave points. You can consume weave points in order to regain up to a 8th level spell slot, which consumes 2 weave points per spell slot level. Additionally, you can use your weave points to augment you spells. Chose two metamagic feats, each can be invoked upon a spell by expending weave points.</p>
     	</description>
      <sheet>
      	<description>Whenenver you cast a spell, are subject of a spell, trigger a spell or enter the area effect of a spell, you gain hit points equal to twice the level of the spell. If doing so would grant you more hit points than you can have, you gain temporary hit points, that do not vanish after long rests, equal to the amount of excess hit points received. Furthermore you gain a number of weave points equal to the level of the spell. You may store up to {{weave-points}} weave points. You can consume weave points in order to regain up to a 8th level spell slot, which consumes 2 weave points per spell slot level. Additionally, you can use your weave points to augment you spells.</description>
      </sheet>
       <rules>
     	 <stat name="weave-points" value="level:wizard" />
     	 <stat name="weave-points" value="level:wizard" />
     	 <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Weave Magic" supports="Weave Magic" level="14" number="2"/>
       </rules>
  	</element>

  	<!-- Metamagic Options -->
  <element name="Careful Spell" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLACKHOLE_CAREFUL_SPELL">
    <supports>Weave Magic</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>When you cast a spell that forces other creatures to make a saving throw, you can protect some of those creatures from the spell’s full force. To do so, you spend 1 sorcery point and choose a number of those creatures up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one creature). A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the spell.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you cast a spell that forces other creatures to make a saving throw, you can protect some of those creatures from the spell’s full force. To do so, you spend 1 weave point and choose a number of those creatures equal to the weave points spent up to your intelligence modifier. A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the spell.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <element name="Distant Spell" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLACKHOLE_DISTANT_SPELL">
    <supports>Weave Magic</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>When you cast a spell that has a range of 5 feet or greater, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double the range of the spell. When you cast a spell that has a range of touch, you can spend 1 sorcery point to make the range of the spell 30 feet.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you cast a spell that has a range of 5 feet or greater, you can spend 1 weave point to double the range of the spell. When you cast a spell that has a range of touch, you can spend 1 weave point to make the range of the spell 30 feet.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <element name="Extended Spell" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLACKHOLE_EXTENDED_SPELL">
    <supports>Weave Magic</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>When you cast a spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can spend 1 weave point to double its duration, to a maximum duration of 24 hours.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you cast a spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can spend 1 weave point to double its duration, to a maximum duration of 24 hours.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <element name="Quickened Spell" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLACKHOLE_QUICKEND_SPELL">
    <supports>Weave Magic</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>When you cast a spell that has a casting time of 1 action, you can spend 3 weave points to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you cast a spell that has a casting time of 1 action, you can spend 3 weave points to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <element name="Subtle Spell" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLACKHOLE_SUBTLE_SPELL">
    <supports>Weave Magic</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>When you cast a spell, you can spend 1 weave point to cast it without any somatic or verbal components.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you cast a spell, you can spend 1 weave point to cast it without any somatic or verbal components.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <element name="Twinned Spell" type="Archetype Feature" source="NOS" id="ID_NOS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLACKHOLE_TWINNED_SPELL">
    <supports>Weave Magic</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>When you cast a spell that targets only one creature and doesn’t have a range of self, you can spend a number of weave points equal to the spell’s level to target a second creature in range with the same spell (1 weave point if the spell is a cantrip).</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you cast a spell that targets only one creature and doesn’t have a range of self, you can spend a number of weave points equal to the spell’s level to target a second creature in range with the same spell (1 weave point if the spell is a cantrip).</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  </elements>
